Guide to the Department of Germanic Languages, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, circa 1929-1989; Accession 1990-A-122
  - Current administrative and correspondence
    - 1.8 Standards and Regulations, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 770)
    - 1.10 DUS Staff Meetings, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 771)
    - 1.11 Live file/Departmental, 1967-1977 (Box 11, Folder 772)
    - 1.12 Old Departmental Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 11, Folder 773)
    - 1.13 Interdepartmental Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 774)
    - 1.14 Live Outside Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 11, Folder 775)
    - 1.15 Response to Requests for information, 1963-1978 (Box 11, Folder 776)
    - 1.17 Old Undergraduate Course Programs, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 777)
    - 1.18 Current Placement of Students, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 778)
    - 1.19 Deans/Registrar: Policies under Discussion, 1963-1976 (Box 11, Folder 779)
    - 1.19 Letters to Deans. Registrar/DUS, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 780)
    - 1.20 Departmental Policies and Matters, 1966-1974 (Box 11, Folder 781)
    - 1.21 Departmental Minutes, 1965-1978 (Box 11, Folder 782)
    - 1.22 Honor Standards, 1965-1972 (Box 11, Folder 783)
    - 1.23 Proctors, 1966-1971 (Box 11, Folder 784)
    - 1.24 Teaching Fellows, Yale, 1977-1979 (Box 11, Folder 785)
    - 1.24 TA Evaluations, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 786)
    - 1.25 Teaching Repertoires, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 787)
    - Courses, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 788)
    - Departmental Course Syllabi. Spring, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 789)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 790)
  - Majors, special duties, miscellaneous
    - 2.1 DUS File on Majors (old), 1963-1968 (Box 11, Folder 791)
    - 2.1.8 German Majors, 1969-1979
      - 1969-1970 (Box 11, Folder 792)
      - 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 793)
      - 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 794)
      - 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 795)
      - 1976-1977 (Box 11, Folder 796)
      - 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 797)
      - 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 798)
    - Reports on Senior Majors -Essays, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 799)
    - Senior Majors, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 800)
    - 2.1.b German Majors: Correspondence, 1964-1978 (Box 11, Folder 801)
    - 2.1.c German Majors: Pamphlets and Reading Lists, 1967-1971 (Box 11, Folder 802)
    - 2.1.d Combined BA -MA, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 803)
    - 2.2 Yale College Series (publishers of Senior Essays), 1966-1978 (Box 11, Folder 804)
    - 2.3 Old German Majors' Examinations, 1964-1978 (Box 11, Folder 805)
    - 2.4 Donald Annis Prize, 1940-1967 (Box 11, Folder 806)
    - 2.4 Scott/Book/2 other prizes, 1963-1982 (Box 12, Folder 807)
    - 2.4 Book/Scott/Annis Prizes et al., 1979 (Box 12, Folder 808)
    - 2.4 Book/Scott/Annis Prizes, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 809)
    - 2.5 Course Material Evaluation/Student Advisory/Graduate Grievance Committee, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 810)
    - 2.6 Departmental Libraries, 1974-1960 (Box 12, Folder 811)
    - 2.1 Statistics/Grades/General Enrollment, 1964-1978 (Box 12, Folder 812)
    - 2.8 Fulbright, 1964-1979 (Box 12, Folder 813)
    - 2.9 Overseas Programs and Work Abroad, 1966-1971 (Box 12, Folder 814)
    - 2.10 Computer Center, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 815)
    - 2.11 Yale German Club, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 816)
    - 2.12 Yale German Club: Planning, 1962-1967 (Box 12, Folder 817)
    - 2.13 Tape Recordings, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 818)
    - 2.14 Konsulat/Goethe Society, 1964-1976 (Box 12, Folder 819)
    - 2.15 Language Lab File, 1968-1973 (Box 12, Folder 820)
    - 2.15 Language Lab/ A-V Center, 1965-1969 (Box 12, Folder 821)
    - 2.15 Language Lab - Summer Language Institute, 1968-1970 (Box 12, Folder 822)
    - 2.16 Language Teaching Committee, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 823)
    - 2.17 Film Lists, 1963-1971 (Box 12, Folder 824)
    - 2.18 Schallplatten/Einkaufs/Vorschlagliste (1962), 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 825)
    - 2.19 Libraries/A-V Facilities/phono records (dept.), 1964-1972 (Box 12, Folder 826)
    - 2.20 Placement and Placement Tests, 1964-1972 (Box 12, Folder 827)
    - 2.21 AATG, 1964-1971 (Box 12, Folder 828)
    - 2.22 AATG Contest, 1965-1970 (Box 12, Folder 829)
    - 2.23 Northeast Conference, 1966-1977 (Box 12, Folder 830)
    - 2.24 ETS Test, 1967 (Box 12, Folder 831)
    - 2.25 Junior Science and Humanities Symposium, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 832)
    - 2.26 Carnegie Teaching Fellowships, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 833)
    - 2.26.a Prize Teaching Fellowships, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 834)
    - 2.27 Information on Study Skills Office, 1965-1967 (Box 12, Folder 835)
    - 2.28 Teaching Aid Project, 1965-1971 (Box 12, Folder 836)
    - 2.29 ERIC -Teaching of Foreign Languages, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 837)
    - 3.1 Elections/Enrollments/Master Sheets, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 838)
    - 3.2 Teacher Training Programs, 1964-1978 (Box 12, Folder 839)
    - 3.3 Teacher Training Supply, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 840)
    - 3.4 Meeting blanks, undated (Box 12, Folder 841)
    - 3.5 Freshman placement blanks (lacking), undated (Box 12, Folder 842)
    - 3.6 Teaching Programs/spec. duties/Moore Fund, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 843)
    - 3.7 Reading Lists -German Majors, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 844)
    - 3.8 Class Count (Sep -Oct), n. d. (Box 13, Folder 845)
    - 3.9 Proctoring Sheets, n. d. (Box 13, Folder 846)
    - 3.10 Address lists, undated (Box 13, Folder 847)
    - 3.11 Hour Exams and Finals of all courses, 1966-1968 (Box 13, Folder 848)
    - 3.12 Curriculum Revision, 1968-1978 (Box 13, Folder 849)
    - German 15, 1976-1977 (Box 13, Folder 850)
    - 3.13 German 18, 1967-1978 (Box 13, Folder 851)
    - German 19, 1970-1976 (Box 13, Folder 852)
    - 3.14 German 22, 1963-1966 (Box 13, Folder 853)
    - 3.15 German 23/130, 1962-1978 (Box 13, Folder 854)
    - German 25, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 855)
    - 3.16 German 30, 1962-1966 (Box 13, Folder 856)
    - 3.17 German 32, 1965-1973 (Box 13, Folder 857)
    - 3.18 German 41 and above, 1963-1977 (Box 13, Folder 858)
    - German 118, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 859)
    - German 125, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 860)
    - German 130, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 861)
    - CCL Reserve Lists for courses by since-departed persons, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 862)
    - 3.19 Swedish, 1966-1970 (Box 13, Folder 863)
    - 3.19.a Dutch, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 864)
    - 3.20 Summer Language Institute
      - 1967 (Box 13, Folder 865)
      - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 866)
      - 1969 (Box 13, Folder 867)
      - 1970 (Box 13, Folder 868)
      - 1971 (Box 13, Folder 869)
      - 1972 (Box 13, Folder 870)
      - 1973 (Box 13, Folder 871)
      - 1974 (Box 13, Folder 822)
      - 1975 (Box 13, Folder 873)
      - 1976 (Box 13, Folder 874)
    - 3.21 Summer Programs, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 875)
    - Osterle Materials. G-l Syllabus, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 876)
    - European Studies Materials I, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 877)
    - European Studies Materials II, 1970-1973 (Box 13, Folder 878)
    - The Experiment in International Living, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 879)
    - Study Abroad/Junior Year Abroad
      - 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 880)
      - 1965-1966 (Box 14, Folder 881)
      - 1966-1967 (Box 14, Folder 882)
      - 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 883)
      - 1968-1973 (Box 14, Folder 884)
    - Study Abroad (Box 14, Folder 885)
    - General Information -Study Abroad (Box 14, Folder 886)
  - Freshman placement/AP/Obsolete materials/Blue, white bulletins
    - 4.1 Blue Bulletin
      - 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 887)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 888)
      - 1967-1970 (Box 14, Folder 889)
    - 4.2 Blue Bulletins: old course descriptions (Box 14, Folder 890)
    - 4.3 White Pamphlet: course schedules (Box 14, Folder 891)
    - 4.4 Advanced Placement (Box 14, Folder 892-893)
    - 4.5 Old Advanced Placement (Box 14, Folder 894)
    - 4.5 Old AP (before 1964) (Box 14, Folder 895)
    - 4.5 AP Conference: 24-26 Jun, Nashville TN (Box 14, Folder 896)
    - 4.6 AP Program: Materials (Box 14, Folder 897)
    - 4.7 Old Elections (Box 14, Folder 898)
    - 4.8 Old (Aug) freshman enrollment/placement (Box 14, Folder 899)
    - 4.9 Freshman placement records (Class of '68) (Box 14, Folder 900)
    - 4.9 Placement Records (Box 14, Folder 901)
    - 4.10 Teaching Evaluations (Box 14, Folder 902)
    - Freshman Placement Record Sheets
      - 4.11, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 903)
      - 4.12, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 904)
      - 4.13, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 905)
      - 4.14, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 906)
      - 4.15, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 907)
      - 1975 (lacking) (Box 14, Folder 908)
      - 1976 (Box 14, Folder 909)
      - 1977 (Box 14, Folder 910)
      - 1978 (lacking) (Box 14, Folder 911)
      - 1980 (lacking) (Box 14, Folder 912)
      - 1981 (Box 14, Folder 913)
    - 4.16 Placement Exams, undated (Box 14, Folder 914)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970-1989
    - II.20 Prizes, 1977-1981 (Box 14, Folder 915)
    - 21 Graduate Students Recruiting, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 916)
    - 23 A -B, 1976-1988 (Box 14, Folder 917)
    - 23 C -D, 1976-1989 (Box 14, Folder 918)
    - 23 E -F, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 919)
    - 23 G -H, 1976-1987 (Box 14, Folder 920)
    - 23 I -J (lacking), 1976 (Box 14, Folder 921)
    - 23 K -L, 1976-1984 (Box 14, Folder 922)
    - 23 M -N, 1976-1984 (Box 14, Folder 923)
    - 23 O -P -Q, 1976-1985 (Box 14, Folder 924)
    - 23 R -S, 1976-1981 (Box 14, Folder 925)
    - 23 T -U, 1976-1982 (Box 14, Folder 926)
    - 23 V -W, 1976-1988 (Box 14, Folder 927)
    - 23 X -Y -Z, 1976-1977 (Box 14, Folder 928)
    - 24 Director of Graduate, 1983-1987 (Box 14, Folder 929)
    - 31 Curriculum Committee, 1977-1979 (Box 14, Folder 930)
- Records, circa 1967-1987; Accession 1990-A-131
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022
  - III. 1.1. Purchase of books, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1.2. Communication department, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 2.1. Dean Yale College/Dean Graduate School, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 2.2. Secretary's Office, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 2.3. Office of Facilities Planning, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 2.4. Housing Bureau, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 2.5. Computer Center, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 2.6. Language Lab/Audiovisual Center, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 2.9. Committee/Council/Division of the Humanities/Whitney Humanities Center, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 2.10. Comptroller's Office/Finance and Administration, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 2.14. Safety policy and Safety organizations, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 2.15. Personnel Office, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 2.15.a. Local 34, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 2.19.a. Director of Undergraduate Studies (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 2.28. Grants and Contracts, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 3.1. Courses general/Women's Studies, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 3.2. Course curricular discussion, Curricular Committee, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 3.3. Course of Studies Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 3.4. Yale College, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 3.5. Election and Enrollment Statistics, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 3.8. Faculty Committee on Teaching and Learning, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 3.11. College Seminars, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 4.1. Teaching Assignments, 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 4.3. Bursary Students, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 4.6. Junior Year Abroad, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 4.6a. Scandinavian Foundation, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - 4.7. Majors/Literature Majors, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - IV.1.1. Directories and Rosters, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1.3. Circulars, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1.4. Tutors, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1.6. MONATSHEFTE/Other Journal entries, 1982-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 2.0. Committee on Graduate Instruction in German Literature, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 2.1. Graduate Courses, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 2.2. College Seminars, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 2.5. Summer Language Institute, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 2.10. Film Course, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - 3.1. Cocktail Party, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - 3.2. Lecturers and Visitors (general), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - 3.3. Woodward Lectures Record/Bromley Lecture Fund/Trumbull Lecture Fund, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 3.5. Special Events, current year, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 4.0. General Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 4.1. Job Applications, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 4.2. Vacancies- Elsewhere, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - 4.3. Graduate Schools Elsewhere, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - 4.6. Graduate Courses, Historical File Beginning with 1984-1985, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - V.2.1. German, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - 2.1a. Embassy of DDR, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - 3.2. Goethe House, New York and Goethe Institutes, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - 3.3. Modern Language Association- ADFL, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - 4.0. Lothar Hausmann Memorial Fund, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - 4.1. Fellows and Lectureships general/ Prizes, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - 4.1.1. Morse Fellowships, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - 4.1.2. Wortspiele, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - 4.1.3. Fulbright Fellowships, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - 4.4. Yale Funds, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - 4.6. Moore Fund, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - 5.2. Leavenworth Professorship, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - 5.3. Foreign Curriculum Consultant Program/ Grants from U.S. Office of Education, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Stanford Program, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Bursary Students, 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - The Germanic Tutor, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Outside Activity Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - 1986 Business (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Grade Verification for Faculty no longer at Yale, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Graduate Student Courses, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Expenses Yale Press, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Hilyard/Weigand, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Agreement between Yale and Local 34, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Miscellaneous memoranda and forms, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - David T. Ware, "The Ego in Isolation: Five Studies of Madness in German Literature", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Mark Felker, "The Trinity in the Theology of Meister Eckhart", undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Mary Alice Harbison, "Order and Creative Chaos: Theme and Narrative Technique in the Newest Novels of Irmtraud Morgner and Gunter Grass", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Hannes Jarka, "Stil, Gefuhl, und die Objektivitat des Erzahlers", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Sarah Bernstein, "Heads You Win, Tails I Lose: A Study of Kafka's 'Der Bau' and Other Stories", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Elizabeth C. Yen, "Fascist Thought in the Novels of Pierre Drieu la Rochelle and Ernst Junger (1936-1945)", 1976 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Rebecca J. Goetze, "The Role of the Writer in Christa Wolf's Kein Ort. Nirgends", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Richard Blum, "Bobrowski's Image of the Eastern Jew", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Douglas Fleming, "Holderlins Leben und Vermeintlicher Wahnsinn", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Kenneth J. Appold, "Reading Hugo Ball's Phonetic Poetry", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Michael Schoenbaum, "The Sword and the Pen in Goethe's Divan", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Robert Jaffee, "Jewish Aspects of Kafka's 'A Report to the Academy'", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Jacqueline Pardo, "Sarah Kirsch: 'Wiepersdoff'. A Poet Searches Identity", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Susan Hunt, "Marginalia in Abraham von Franckenberg's Raphael", undated (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Caroline K. Murphy, "The Image of the Dike in Theodor Storm's 'Der Schimmelreiter'", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Anne P. Sommers, "Rilke's Religious Mythology", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - B. Benedikt Koehler, "Theory and Practice of Jean Paul's Poetics", undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Professor Peucker, Figures, undated (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Douglas Fleming, "Johannes Bobrowski: Die Pruzzische Elegie und Kunstlerisches Engagement", undated (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Betsy Kolbert, "'Fantasie und Handling': Theatricality and Actuality in the Drama of Peter Weiss", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Heidi R. Sokol, "The Reconstuction of German Education", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - David Black, "Mediation and Transport in the Hymen an die Nacht by Novalis", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Thomas H. Rodde, "Distance and Creation: The Expression of Humanity in Doktor Faustus and Finnegan's Wake", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Nicholas Olcott, "Luise, Sara and Emilia: The Private Family and the Assertion of a Bourgeois Morality", 1978 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Randall Dante Costa, "Homecoming and Landscape in the work of Friedrich Holderlin and Caspar David Friedrich", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 94 - 95)
  - Rainer Karasz, "'Die unerhorte Mitte': The Poet as Demiurge in Rainer Maria Rilke's Sonnets to Orpheus", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Thomas B. Mooney, "Tragodie und Radikalismus", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Mark Kadar, "Leverkeuhn, Nietzsche, and the Crisis of Modern Art in Thomas Mann's Doktor Faustus", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Janet Tobias, "The Secret Garden: An Exploration of German and English Children's Literature", 1981 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Rebecca J. Goetze, "Society, Language and Sex-Roles as Obstacles to Creativity in Christa Wolf's Kein Ort. Nirgends", 1983 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Stephen B. Heimann, "An Analysis of Heinrich Heine's Thoughts on the Transience of Goodness and Beauty as Expressed in the Romanzero", 1977 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Daniel E. Faircloth, "The German Swan Knight Tradition", undated (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Beverly A. Ortiz, "Fountain in the Garden: Heine, Women and the Dilemma of Love", 1985 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Michael Wachtel, "Heine's Poetics", 1979 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Michael J. Beiser, "Als das Sprechen noch Geholfen Hat: The Language-Model of Peter Handke", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Claudia Mesch, "Heinrich Boll, the Courageous Moralist", 1982 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - David Lechner, "Authenticity and the 'Massenschlacht'", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Budgets, 1976-1987 (Box 3)
  - Budget-related materials, 1967-1987 (Box 4)
  - Budgets, 1981-1984 (Box 5)
- Syllabi for German 15 and 25 and publishing contracts, 1957-1959; Accession 1993-A-060
  The materials are open for research.
  - Syllabi for German 15 and 25 and publishing contracts, 1957-1959 (Box 1)
- Compiled history of the German Language Department, circa 1957; Accession 1995-A-017
  - Compiled history (1813-1955) of the German Language Department, circa 1957 (Box 1)
- Minutes of meetings, 1968-1969; Accession 1999-A-063
  - Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 1-3)